<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hassan Shahbazi</title>
    <link>https://shahbazi.fi/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hassan Shahbazi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shahbazi.fi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Use S3 instead of Google</title>
      <link>https://shahbazi.fi/posts/s3-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahbazi.fi/posts/s3-backup/</guid>
      <description>This might be a slightly different post of mine as it is not directly related to my work. However, I believe it is a good example of how I used my technical skills in my personal life. The case was relatively simple: I wanted to save money and yet keep my data safe in the cloud. Let me explain the situation first.
Situation For a long time I had chosen to keep separate online archives for my photos and data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My &#39;daybook&#39;</title>
      <link>https://shahbazi.fi/posts/daybook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahbazi.fi/posts/daybook/</guid>
      <description>It was not a long time ago that I started feeling overwhelmed at work. I felt I had a big plate filled with many things that I needed to take care of immediately and I had no power to handle them. It looked like a simple task was taking forever to be done for some unknown reasons. I was constantly blaming myself for not meeting the deadlines for some reasons that I could not see.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save the day with git bisect</title>
      <link>https://shahbazi.fi/posts/git-bisect/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahbazi.fi/posts/git-bisect/</guid>
      <description>Git is probably the one single skill/technology keyword that can be found on CV of almost all people working in the Software industry. It is one of the first things everyone learn even before starting to write the code. This is mostly because of the fact that it is the most widely used version control system, it is easy to learn, and it is very powerful. Here in this article, I don’t intend to discuss about complex or very advanced features, but to talk about a real scenario that I faced recently and how I used one of these features to solve the problem, even though I should simplify the case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Mobile to Cloud. A Journey of a Software Engineer</title>
      <link>https://shahbazi.fi/posts/developer-devops-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahbazi.fi/posts/developer-devops-journey/</guid>
      <description>I believe I have already mentioned in my previous posts about the journey I started as a Software Engineer back in 2011. When I was still early in my bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree, I was asked to join a young team as their iOS developer. It was a great opportunity for me to start my career, and I am very thankful for that. I have learned a lot from that team, and I have always been grateful for the chance they gave me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Standards in Software</title>
      <link>https://shahbazi.fi/posts/standards-in-se/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahbazi.fi/posts/standards-in-se/</guid>
      <description>We, as human being, would like to explain the world we are living in with the simplest possible rules. That is why physicists are looking to find a theory to explain everything. The same motivations are found among other fields&amp;rsquo; experts, including Software Engineers.
This is, however, a bit different in the SE industry. Here, experts are trying to find an optimal way to make software development easy, efficient, and reliable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Career, New Journey</title>
      <link>https://shahbazi.fi/posts/f-secure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahbazi.fi/posts/f-secure/</guid>
      <description>When I started my journey as a Software Engineer back in 2011, I was asked to develop iOS applications. It was a small team, and I was joined as an intern, so I took the opportunity and to be honest, it was a wise choice. Working on Mobile projects, in my opinion, is always a good starting point for recently graduated or even students as it is easier to learn and still requires knowledge that helps newbies to get better in software development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Meditation Leave - Until 2022 Jan 1st</title>
      <link>https://shahbazi.fi/posts/meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahbazi.fi/posts/meditation/</guid>
      <description>In my culture, or to be more precise, in Islamic culture, there is an approach to meditate and &amp;ldquo;clean&amp;rdquo; yourself by doing (or repeating) a behaviour for 40 days. It is called 40ish method, or what we call it in Persian, Chelle Neshini. This is not only in Islam, but in many other religious there is a same sort of instruction. Although I&amp;rsquo;m not a religious man and this doesn&amp;rsquo;t aim to improve my relation with God, I think I would like to give it a try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kernel Crash Fixed! Lessons Learned</title>
      <link>https://shahbazi.fi/posts/kernel-crash-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahbazi.fi/posts/kernel-crash-1/</guid>
      <description>It all started back in January 2021, when I saw Greg&amp;rsquo;s tweet about a Kernel mentorship program for Spring 2021.
It was a huge opportunity for me, a developer who loves Linux and enjoys working on open-source. Indeed, I had tried once to submit a patch, but it was rejected because I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the required knowledge for working on Kernel. Therefore, I applied for the program so quickly that I didn&amp;rsquo;t even check the deadline and required tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kernel Patches</title>
      <link>https://shahbazi.fi/posts/kernel-patch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahbazi.fi/posts/kernel-patch/</guid>
      <description>I like spending time on open-source projects. My GitHub profile is full of libraries and tutorials I have made during past years. On top of all, I have a big passion for Linux and the community behind it. In my opinion, Linux is one of the most important and game-changer projects during the history of Computer Science.
I started to study Linux Kernel in 2020, and have tried to make few patches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Era</title>
      <link>https://shahbazi.fi/posts/new-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahbazi.fi/posts/new-design/</guid>
      <description>On the last day of February 2021, I decided to improve how my website looks and feels. The old version was nice, but it was full of useless information and details. I was looking for a minimalist place to share my knowledge, link my social accounts and emails, and help people know me better as a developer and human being. Since I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of heavy animations and fancy UI components, I got impressed extensively by simple examples such as Timo Savola and Sameer Rahmani.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swift &#43; WebAssembly</title>
      <link>https://shahbazi.fi/posts/swift&#43;wasm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shahbazi.fi/posts/swift&#43;wasm/</guid>
      <description>Write once, Run anywhere has been a dream for decades among software companies and developers. The idea of removing duplicated code is not just about doing most with least costs, but also about avoiding disasters of forgetting to update all copies. If you have ever contributed in a large-scale software project (even in a small one), you probably have seen how different teams try to centralize core solutions and algorithms to avoid duplication.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
